http://www.amcp.org/privacy-policy

Managed Care Pharmacy 101
What is Managed Care Pharmacy?
directory_links
Get started on AMCP Learn.
November 2020 | Vol. 26, Issue 11
Healthcare Resource Utilization and Cost Among Patients with Type 1 Diabetes in the United States
Legislative & Regulatory Issues
Rutledge v. The Pharmaceutical Care Management Association (PCMA)
Biosimilar & Interchangeable Drug Products Legislation & Laws
directory_links
New member benefit! Visit AMCP Collaborate.
National Meetings
State Advocacy Coordinator (S.A.C.)
Keyword
Enter your keyword(s)
VISIT AMCP'S DISEASE STATE RESOURCE CENTER Get in-depth information on the most pressing disease states. Learn More Close
Managed Care Pharmacy 101
What is Managed Care Pharmacy?
Legislative & Regulatory Issues
Rutledge v. The Pharmaceutical Care Management Association (PCMA)
Biosimilar & Interchangeable Drug Products Legislation & Laws
National Meetings
State Advocacy Coordinator (S.A.C.)
Who We Are
This is the AMCP Privacy Policy. You can contact us at 675 North Washington Street, Suite 220, Alexandria, VA 22314. We can be reached by email at memberservices@amcp.org, or you can call us at 703-684-2600.
AMCP values individual privacy and we want to give our members, customers and website visitors the opportunity to know what information we collect about them and how they can limit the use of personally-identifiable information beyond the purposes for which they first provided it. At all times, however, AMCP reserves the right to disclose information where required by law or to comply with valid legal process (such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order), to protect AMCP’s rights or property, including without limitation in the event of a transfer of control of AMCP or substantially all of its assets, or during emergencies when safety is at risk.
By visiting the Site, or by using one of the Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Policy. We may amend this Policy at any time; if we make changes to this Policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. We will not apply changes to this policy to personal information previously collected without your prior consent. You are responsible for checking this Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Site following any changes to this Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.
Data We Collect and How We Use It
Personally Identifiable Information
We collect your email address if you communicate with us by email or register for an AMCP product or service, as well as other information that you might supply voluntarily, such as survey and demographic information.
If you purchase a product or service at our site, we will also ask for your credit card number or other account number you wish to be charged. We do not give out your credit card or other account information to third parties unless you authorize us to do so or if it is necessary to fulfill our responsibilities, including, but not limited to, delivering a product or service you order.
We may use this information to respond to an email or other inquiry or request, to help improve our services, to customize your experience at our website, or to send updates or notices about our organization and the products we offer that we think may be of interest to you. We may also combine this information with other generally or publicly available information to help us identify visitors’ preferences or interests. We may provide information that identifies you to companies that assist us in these activities, such as helping us fulfill your request for a product, service or information.
AMCP collects information from its members (including names, addresses, business phone numbers, business fax numbers, and email addresses) for inclusion in a membership directory that is included in the membership directory. Access to directory information is also available only to AMCP’s members on AMCP’s website. Further AMCP may occasionally provide, sell, or rent limited data to third parties, including companies that offer products and services for sale to AMCP’s members. This limited data includes names, job titles, companies/organizations, and business addresses, but do not include business phone numbers, business fax numbers, or email addresses.
Cookies & Web Beacons
In order to help enhance the performance and functionality of the Site, we utilize session, persistent and third-party “cookies” that store a small piece of data on a users’ computers and collect certain information about the users’ visit to our Site. We also use cookies to understand users’ browsing and buying activities so that we can measure the success of online advertising campaigns we run on the Site. Our Site also uses web beacons (either directly or from our partners), along with cookies, to determine if a user has visited a particular website. These beacons aid in providing more relevant advertising to the user, as well measuring the success of an advertising campaign, but provide no personally identifiable information.
Cookies are small text files that web servers typically send to users’ computer when they visit a website. Cookies are stored as text files on users’ hard drive, and can be accessed by web servers when the user visits a website or views an advertisement. A session cookie is a cookie that stores information as a user is using the Site but is deleted once the browser session is finished. A persistent cookie is a cookie that stores information as a user utilizes the Site and stores and uses that information in connection with future visits of the user to the Site. Third-party cookies and/or web beacons are cookies or web beacons provided by our technology and/or advertising partners. Any third-party cookie or web beacon that we authorize for use on the Site only collects that information described below for the same stated purposes as if we were directly collecting the information. For a third-party cookie or web beacon, the third-party will have access to the collected information in order to provide us with information or services to enhance the performance and functionality of the Site.
The cookies and web beacons we use collect non-personally identifiable information about users of the Site, including: IP address, browser used to access the site, date and time, the URL of the page being loaded, users who have visited a particular website(s), any previously assigned cookie identification (a unique identifier assigned to a user to identify repeat visitors), browser window size, the geographic location of the user, device and operating system used to access the Site. The information we collect from these cookies and web beacons is used to determine information about a user’s visit to our Site, including the number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed, navigation history through the website, and other statistics. This information is used to enhance the users experience while visiting our Site and to improve the performance of our Site by, among other things, allowing us to monitor Site performance, making the Site easier to use, measuring the effectiveness of promotional placements, and tailoring the Site (including the ads and offers a user receives) to better match a user’s interests and preferences.
Users who prefer not to accept cookies can set their Internet browser to notify them when they receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being placed on their hard drive. If you consent to our collection of cookies and you subsequently wish to withdraw your consent, you will need to manage the settings on your web browser to delete all cookies and disallow further acceptance of cookies. Please note that disabling cookies on your browser will prevent us from tracking your activities in relations to our Site, however, it may also disable some of the functions and features of the Site and the Site may not work properly.
By continuing to use our Site, you are agreeing to our placing cookies and/or web beacons on your computer in order to analyze the way you use our Site. Please read this cookie policy carefully for more details about the information we collect when you use the Site.
If you do not wish to accept cookies or web beacons in connection with your use of this Site, please discontinue use of the Site.
How You Can Control and Update Data About You
We want to be sure that we keep only the most accurate and up-to-date information about you in our records. Therefore, whenever you believe that your contact information needs to be updated, you can email us at memberservices@amcp.org to correct or update your contact information.
You may choose at any time to remove your name, telephone and fax numbers, and postal and email addresses from the lists we use to send notices or updates and elect not to receive correspondence from us by emailing at memberservices@amcp.org. You may also opt out from any email group by following the opt-out links at the bottom of emails we send you.
Other Internet sites you visit — including those linked from the AMCP website — may have their own privacy policies or no policy at all. Other websites might use personal information differently than our policy permits. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policies of any site before providing any personal information.
Data Integrity and Security
We use state-of-the-art technology to keep any information you provide as secure as possible. We also have in place privacy protection control contractual obligations with our vendors designed to ensure that personal data is protected from unauthorized access or disclosure. All AMCP employees must abide by AMCP’s Privacy Policy.
Become an AMCP member today!
Discover new ways to improve performance, increase efficiency, and grow your network.
What is Managed Care Pharmacy?
Rutledge v. The Pharmaceutical Care Management Association (PCMA)
Biosimilar & Interchangeable Drug Products Legislation & Laws
State Advocacy Coordinator (S.A.C.)
